nascompares.com 2019-05-05

# Privacy Policy - NAS Compares

**_Data Privacy Notice_**

**NAScompares.com**  respect your privacy and are determined to protect your personal data.

All our procedures comply with the Data Protection Act (1998), the Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard (PCI DSS), the Privacy and Electronic Communications (EC Directive) Regulations 2003, and the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) (EU) (2016).

The purpose of this privacy notice is to inform you as to how we look after your personal data when you visit our website, regardless of where and how you visit it. We’ll also tell you about your privacy rights and how the data protection law protects you.

  1. **WHO WE ARE AND IMPORTANT  INFORMATION **

**_What is the purpose of this privacy notice?_**

This privacy notice aims to give you information on how we collect and process your personal data through your use of this website, including any data you may provide through this website when you contact us or sign up to our newsletter.

You must read this privacy notice together with any other privacy notice we may provide on specific occasions when we are collecting or processing personal data about you so that you are fully aware of how and why we are using your data. This privacy notice supplements the other notices and is not intended to override them.

  2. **THE PERSONAL DATA WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU**

Personal data, or personal information, means any information about an individual from which that person can be identified. You can find out more about personal data from the [Information Commissioners Office](https://ico.org.uk/global/contact-us/).

We may collect, use, store and transfer different kinds of personal data about you which we have grouped together as follows:

  * **Identity Data  **includes First Name, Last Name, User Name, Title.
  * **Contact Data  **includes Billing Address, Delivery Address, Email Address, Telephone Numbers.
  * **Technical data**  includes IP address, Session data, Browser type and version, Location, Operating system and Platform, Technology on the devices you use to access this website.
  * **Usage data**  includes Information about how you use our website, products and services.
  * **Marketing and communications data**  includes your preferences in receiving marketing from us and your communication preferences.

  3. **HOW WE COLLECT YOUR PERSONAL DATA**

We use different methods to collect data from and about you including:

  * You may give us your identity, contact and financial data by filling in forms or by corresponding with us by post, phone, email or otherwise. This includes personal data you provide when you: 
    * Request our advice service to be sent to you;
  * **Automated technologies or interactions**. As you interact with our website, we may automatically collect Technical Data about your equipment, browsing actions and patterns. We collect this personal data by using cookies and other similar technologies. Please see our cookie policy <https://nascompares.com/cookie/> for further details.

  4. **HOW WE USE YOUR PERSONAL DATA**

We will only use your personal data when the law allows us to. Most commonly, we will use your personal data in the following circumstances:

  * **Legitimate Interest  **this means the interest of our business in conducting and managing our business to enable us to give you the best service/product and the most secure experience. We make sure we consider and balance any potential impact on you (both positive and negative) and your rights before we process your personal data for our legitimate interests. We do not use your personal data for activities where our interests are overridden by the impact on you (unless we have your consent or are otherwise required or permitted to by law). You can obtain further information about how we assess our legitimate interests against any potential impact on you in respect of specific activities by contacting us directly.

**PURPOSES FOR WHICH WE WILL USE YOUR PERSONAL DATA**

We have set out below, in a table format, a description of all the ways we plan to use your personal data, with the legal bases we rely on to do so.

Note that we may process your personal data for more than one lawful ground depending on the specific purpose for which we are using your data. Please contact us at <https://nascompares.com/contact-us/> if you need details about the specific legal ground we are relying on to process your personal data where more than one ground has been set out in the table below.

**Purpose/Activity** | **Type of data** | **Lawful basis for processing**  
---|---|---  
To manage our relationship with you which will include: Notifying you about changes to our terms or privacy policy; Asking you to leave a review or take a survey | Identity. Contact. Profile. Marketing & Communications. | Performance of a contract with you. Necessary to comply with a legal obligation.  
Necessary for our legitimate interests (to keep our records updated and to study how customers use our products/services)  
To administer and protect our business and this website (including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, system maintenance, support, reporting and hosting of data) | Identity. Contact. Technical. | Necessary for our legitimate interests (for running our business, provision of administration and IT services, network security, to prevent fraud and in the context of a business reorganisation or group restructuring exercise). Necessary to comply with a legal obligation  
To deliver relevant website content and advertisements to you and measure or understand the effectiveness of the advertising we serve to you | Identity. Contact. Profile. Usage. Marketing & Communications. Technical | Necessary for our legitimate interests (to study how customers use our products/services, to develop them, to grow our business and to inform our marketing strategy)  
To use data analytics to improve our website, products/services, marketing, customer relationships and experiences | Technical. Usage. | Necessary for our legitimate interests (to define types of customers for our products and services, to keep our website updated and relevant, to develop our business and to inform our marketing strategy)  
To make suggestions and recommendations to you about goods or services that may be of interest to you | Identity. Contact. Technical.  Usage. Profile | Necessary for our legitimate interests (to develop our products/services and grow our business)  
  
**_Marketing_**

We strive to provide you with choices regarding certain personal data uses, particularly around marketing and advertising.

We have established the following personal data control mechanisms:

**_Third-party marketing_**

We will get your express opt-in consent before we share your personal data with any company outside the company for marketing purposes.

**_Opting out_**

You can ask us to stop sending you marketing messages at any time by letting us know https://nascompares.com/contact-us/.

**_Cookies_**

You can set your browser to refuse all or some browser cookies or to alert you when websites set or access cookies. If you disable or refuse cookies, please note that some parts of this website may become inaccessible or not function properly. For more information about the cookies we use, please see <https://nascompares.com/cookie/>

**_Change of purpose_**

We will only use your personal data for the purposes for which we collected it, unless we reasonably consider that we need to use it for another reason and that reason is compatible with the original purpose. If you wish to get an explanation as to how the processing for the new purpose is compatible with the original purpose, please contact us directly.

If we need to use your personal data for an unrelated purpose, we will notify you and we will explain the legal basis which allows us to do so.

Please note that we may process your personal data without your knowledge or consent, in compliance with the above rules, where this is required or permitted by law.

  5. **WHO WE SHARE YOUR PERSONAL DATA WITH**

We do not share any of your information to third parties.

  6. **INTERNATIONAL TRANSFERS**

We do not transfer your personal data outside the European Economic Area (EEA).

  7. **DATA SECURITY**

We have put in place appropriate security measures to prevent your personal data from being accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorized way, altered or disclosed. In addition, we limit access to your personal data to those employees, agents, contractors and other third parties who have a business need to know. They will only process your personal data on our instructions and they are subject to a duty of confidentiality.

We have put in place procedures to deal with any suspected personal data breach and will notify you and any applicable regulator of a breach where we are legally required to do so.

  8. **DATA RETENTION**

We will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfill the purposes we collected it for.

To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements.

We retain basic information about our customers (name and email) for five years after they cease being customers for insurance and product guarantee purposes.

In some circumstances you can ask us to delete your data: see  **Your legal rights  **below for further information.

In some circumstances, we may anonymize your personal data (so that it can no longer be associated with you) for research or statistical purposes in which case we may use this information indefinitely without further notice to you.

  9. **YOUR LEGAL RIGHTS**

Unless subject to an exemption under the data protection laws, you have the following rights with respect to your personal data:

  * The right to request a copy of the personal data which we hold about you;
  * The right to request that we correct any personal data if it is found to be inaccurate or out of date;
  * The right to request your personal data is erased where it is no longer necessary to retain such data;
  * The right to withdraw your consent to the processing at any time, where consent was the lawful basis for processing your data;
  * The right to request that we provide you with your personal data and where possible, to transmit that data directly to another data controller, (known as the right to data portability), where applicable i.e. where our processing is based on consent or is necessary for the performance of our contract with you or where we process your data by automated means);
  * The right, where there is a dispute in relation to the accuracy or processing of your personal data, to request a restriction is placed on further processing;
  * The right to object to our processing of personal data, where applicable i.e. where processing is based on our legitimate interests (or in a performance of a task in the public interest/exercise of official authority); direct marketing or processing for the purposes of scientific/historical research and statistics).

If you wish to exercise any of the rights set out above, please contact us at <https://nascompares.com/contact-us/>

**_No fee required – with some exceptions_**

You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal data (or to exercise any of the other rights). However, we may charge a reasonable admin fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive. Alternatively, we may refuse to comply with your request in these circumstances.

**_What we may need from you_**

We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure your right to access your personal data (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is a security measure to ensure that personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. We may also contact you to ask you for further information in relation to your request to speed up our response.

**_Time limit to respond_**

We try to respond to all legitimate requests within one month. Occasionally it may take us longer than a month if your request is particularly complex or you have made a number of requests. In this case, we will notify you and keep you updated.

  10. **Changes to this notice and your duty to inform us of changes**

This version was last updated on 25th May 2018, and historic versions can be obtained by contacting us.

From 25th May 2018 there will be changes in data protection laws and we will then be able to respond to some of your requests (for example, a request for the transfer of your personal data). We are still working towards getting our systems ready for some of these changes.

Please keep us informed if your personal data changes during your relationship with us. It is important that the personal data we hold about you is accurate and current.

  11. **Queries, requests or concerns**

To exercise all relevant rights, queries or complaints in relation to this policy or any other data protection matter between you and us, please in the first instance contact us at <https://nascompares.com/contact-us/>

If this does not resolve your complaint to your satisfaction, you have the right to lodge a complaint with the [Information Commissioners Office](https://ico.org.uk/global/contact-us/) on 0303 123 1113 or via email <https://ico.org.uk/global/contact-us/email/> or at the Information Commissioner’s Office, Wycliffe House, Water Lane, Wilmslow, Cheshire, SK9 5AF, England, UK.
